Privacy
=======

Privacy Policy
==============

**Last update:**  16\. December 2024

This data privacy statement applies to (amongst others):

* additional web pages of World4You Internet Services GmbH, provided that their data privacy statement link leads to this page

The gender-specific spelling has been omitted for the sole purpose of better readability. All personal names on the website (and all integrated documents) are therefore to be understood as gender-neutral. The shortened form of language has purely editorial reasons and does not contain any evaluation.

In cases of doubt, the German version of this privacy statement shall apply.

Thank you for your interest in the information on our website!

With the help of this Privacy Policy we would like to inform the users of our website about the type, scope and purpose of the personal data processed. Personal data in this context is all information that can be used to personally identify you as a user of our website (theoretically in an alternative way or by linking various data), including your IP address. Information that is stored in cookies is generally not or only in exceptional cases personally identifiable. However, cookies are covered by specific regulations that makes the permissibility of the use of cookies dependent on their purpose to a large extent on the active consent of the user.

In a general section of this Privacy Policy, we provide you with information on data protection, which generally applies to our processing of data, including data collection on our website. In particular, you as a data subject will be informed about the rights to which you are entitled.

The terms used in our Privacy Policy and our data protection practice are based on the provisions of the EU General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") and other relevant national legal provisions.

### **1\. Name and address of the data controller**

The data controller as set out in the General Data Protection Regulation and other national data protection laws of the Member States as well as any other data protection regulations is:

**World4You Internet Services GmbH**  
FN 232485s  
Wolfgang-Pauli-Straße 2, BT3  
4020 Linz  
Austria

**e:** [dataprotection@world4you.com](mailto:dataprotection@world4you.com)  
**t:** +43 50 5859 

### **2\. General information on data processing**

#### **2.1. Scope of the processing of personal data**

As a general principle, we only collect and use personal data from our users insofar as this is necessary for the provision of a well-functioning website and of our contents and services.

#### **2.2. Legal basis for the processing of personal data**

Insofar as we obtain consent from the data subject for the processing of personal data, Art. 6 Para. 1 Item a of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) serves as the legal basis.

For the processing of personal data necessary for the fulfillment of a contract to which the data subject is party, Art. 6 Para. 1 Item b GDPR serves as the legal basis. This also applies to processing necessary for the performance of pre-contractual measures.

Insofar as the processing of personal data is necessary for the fulfilment of a legal obligation to which our company is subject, Art. 6 Para. 1 Item c GDPR serves as the legal basis.

In the event that the vital interests of the data subject or another natural person make the processing of personal data necessary, Art. 6 Para. 1 Item d GDPR serves as the legal basis.

If the processing is necessary for the safeguarding of a legitimate interest of our company or a third party and if the interests, fundamental rights and fundamental freedoms of the data subject do not outweigh the aforementioned interest, Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GDPR serves as the legal basis for the processing.

#### **2.3. Erasure of data and storage period**

The personal data of the data subject is erased or anonymised as soon as the purpose of the storage no longer applies. Storage beyond this period may occur if stipulated by the European or national legislators in regulations, laws or other provisions of Union law to which the data controller is subject. The anonymisation or erasure of the data also takes place when a storage term stipulated by the aforementioned norms expires, unless there is a necessity for the continued storage of the data for the conclusion or fulfilment of a contract.

### **3\. Provision of the website**

#### **3.1. Description and scope of the data processing**

Each time our website is called up, our system automatically collects data and information from the computer system of the querying computer.

The following data is collected in doing so:

(1) Information on the browser type and the version used  
(2) The user’s operating system  
(3) The user’s internet service provider  
(4) The user’s IP address  
(5) Date and time of access  
(6) Websites from which the user’s system accesses our website  
(7) Subpages and functions that the user calls up  
(8) Websites that are called up by the user’s system from our website

This data is also stored in our system’s log files. Storage of this data together with other personal data of the user does not take place.

#### **3.2. Legal basis for the data processing**

The legal basis for the temporary storage of the data and log files is Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GDPR.

#### **3.3. Purpose of the data processing**

The temporary storage of the IP address by the system is necessary in order to enable the provision of the website to the user’s computer. To this end, the IP address of the user must be stored for the duration of the session.

The storage and analysis in log files takes place so as to ensure the functionality of the website. In addition, this data helps us to optimise the website and ensure the security of our information technology systems. An evaluation of the data for marketing purposes does not take place in this context.

These purposes also form the basis of our legitimate interest in the data processing according to Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GDPR.

#### **3.4. Duration of the storage**

The data is deleted as soon as it is no longer required for the achievement of the purpose for which it was collected. In the event that the data is recorded for the provision of the website, this is the case once the respective session is ended. In the event that the data is stored in log files, this is the case at the latest after fourteen days. Storage beyond this point is not possible. In this case, the IP addresses of the users are deleted or distorted such that association with the inquiring client is no longer possible.

#### **3.5. Option to object or request elimination**

The collection of the data for the provision of the website and the storage of the data in log files is essential for the operation of the website. Consequently, the user has no option to object.

There is an option to object with regard to the evaluation of the subpages and functions that the user calls up in the customer area, webmail or PHPMyAdmin tool, for the purpose of optimising the website (improvement of usability). A settings option in the customer area enables you to declare your objection in this respect:

### **4\. Use of cookies**

#### **4.1. Description and scope of the data processing**

Our website uses cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored on the user’s computer system in the internet browser and by the internet browser. When a user calls up a website, a cookie may be stored on the user’s computer system. This cookie contains a distinctive string of characters that enables the unambiguous identification of the browser if the website is called up again.

We use cookies to make our website more user-friendly. Some elements of our website require the inquiring browser to be identifiable even after changing pages.

The following data is stored and transmitted in the cookies:

(1) Session ID  
(2) Viewport information  
(3) Search function ID

#### **4.2. Legal basis for the data processing**

The legal basis for the processing of personal data using technically necessary cookies is Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GDPR.

The legal basis for the processing of personal data using all other cookies is the consent of the person concerned in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 Item a GDPR.

#### **4.3. Purpose of the technically necessary cookies**

The purpose of using technically necessary cookies is to make the use of websites easier for the user. Some functions of our website cannot be offered without the use of cookies. These functions require the recognition of the browser even after changing pages.

We require cookies for the following applications:

(1) Language settings  
(2) Shopping basket information  
(3) Form validation  
(4) One-page checkout  
(5) Affiliate functions  
(6) Login information  
(7) Responsive behaviour

These purposes also form the basis of our legitimate interest in the processing of personal data according to Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GDPR.

The user data collected using technically necessary cookies is not used for the creation of user profiles.

You can find more information on all other cookies and their purposes below in the sections "Protection against cyber attacks using Wordfence", "Web analysis by Google Analytics" and "Remarketing".

#### **4.4. Duration of the storage, option to object or request elimination**

Cookies are stored on the user’s computer and transmitted to us from there. Hence you as the user have complete control over the use of cookies. By changing the settings in your internet browser, you can deactivate or limit the transmission of cookies. Cookies that have already been stored can be deleted at any time. This can also be carried out automatically. If cookies are deactivated for our website, it is possible that you may no longer be able to use all the functions of the website to their full extent.

If you do not change any settings or delete anything in your internet browser, the necessary technical cookies will remain valid for one month, with the exception of the cookie “copol\_www\_world4you\_com\_optin”. This is technically necessary in order to save your consent to the placement of optional cookies and is only deleted after 10 years, if still present.

### **5\. Newsletter**

#### **5.1. Description and scope of the data processing**

Should you give your express consent to receive newsletters, we may periodically send you electronic newsletters with the content of a commercial nature for promotional purposes. For the purpose of sending the newsletter, the following personal data provided when registering for the newsletter will be used:

* First name, last name
* email address
* Date of birth
* Language

The distribution of the newsletter will be carried out by CleverReach GmbH & Co KG. They ensure the security of your data through appropriate technical and organizational measures that are state ofthe art. As a processor, CleverReach GmbH & Co KG is not permitted to use the personal data provided for purposes other than sending the newsletter. For this purpose, the following data is transmitted to CleverReach GmbH & Co KG: first name, last name, email address, last mail client, date of birth, language, existing products, annual revenue, business customer or private customer, order date, contract duration, termination date, registration date, last login, and registration medium (website, control panel, or external platforms). Your personal data will be transmitted to CleverReach server locations within the EU.

#### **5.2. Legal basis for the data processing**

The provision of data for the newsletter receipt is neither legally nor contractually required and is also not necessary for the conclusion of a contract. Therefore, there is no obligation to provide this data or to give consent to receive a newsletter.

The legal basis for receiving the newsletter is only the consent given for this purpose (Art 6 para 1 lit a DSGVO). If consent is not granted, the newsletter will not be sent.

#### **5.3. Purpose of the data processing**

The processing of the data entered by the user serves to create and deliver the newsletter. 

#### **5.4. Duration of the storage**

The data collected from you for this purpose will be stored by us only for the period in which you receive a newsletter and have not revoked your consent to receive newsletters.

#### **5.5. Option to object or request elimination**

You can revoke the consent you have given us to receive newsletters at any time without giving reasons. To do so, you can send us an e-mail to dataprotection@world4you.com or unsubscribe using the link [https://www.world4you.com/en/newsletter/information](https://www.world4you.com/en/newsletter/information) or via the unsubscribe option provided in the newsletter. However, we would like to point out that all processing/transfers carried out until the revocation remain lawful.

### **6\. Conclusion of contract**

#### **6.1. Description and scope of the data processing**

On our website, we offer users the option of purchasing products and services. This involves entering data into an input screen; this data is then transmitted to us and stored by us.

Obligatory:

* customer type (private/company)
* salutation
* name (first name, last name)
* address (street, house number, zip code, city, country)
* e-mail-address
* phone number
* data for payment depending on the payment method
* depending on top level domain, additional information may be required after purchase

Optional:

* title
* date of birth
* UID (only for corporate customers)
* commercial register number (only for corporate customers)

At the time of registering, furthermore, the following data is also stored:

(1) Information on the browser type and the version used  
(2) The user’s operating system  
(3) The user’s IP address  
(4) Date and time  
(5) Referrer

For the purpose of communication between you and us the following data will be passed on to our customer support platform Dixa ApS, Vimmelskaftet 41 A, 1. Stock, 1161 Copenhagen K, Denmark:

* first name, last name
* e-mail-address
* customer number
* telephone number

For the purpose of setting up and maintaining customer services and internal service landscapes  
the above mentioned obligatory and optional data will be passed on to our affiliated company Arsys  
Internet S.L.U., C. Madre de Dios, 21, 26004 Logroño, La Rioja, Spain.

For the purpose of developing, improving and managing the product portfolio the following data will  
be passed on to our affiliated company united-domains GmbH, Gautinger Straße 10, 82319  
Starnberg, Germany:

* first name, last name
* e-mail-address
* telephone number
* address
* date of birth
* passport number (if specified)
* commercial register number
* UID number

Furthermore, we collect, process and store the data that you store yourself when you use our services. This includes the creation of dynamic backup copies in our backup system.

Disclosure of the data to third parties: in the event of a domain registration, the domain registration data is passed on to a domain name registrar and/or a registration authority.

In the case of payment (e.g. by credit card,  PayPal, Apple Pay, Klarna / Sofortüberweisung), your email address will be passed on to our payment platform provider VIVEUM Payment Systems GmbH, Riemergasse 14/30, 1010 Vienna. When paying by credit card, World4You can request the term or the last four digits of the creditcard from PAYONE for organizational reasons.

In the event of a substantial default in payment, the data may be passed on to a communications service provider, a collection agency, to legal representatives and to the competent court if necessary.

If invoices are sent by post or communication is made by post, your name and your address may be passed on to our service provider WienIT GmbH, Thomas-Klestil-Platz 3, 1030 Vienna for printing and enveloping.

#### **6.2. Legal basis for the data processing**

Insofar as the processing serves for the fulfilment of a contract to which the user is party or for the performance of pre-contractual measures, the legal basis for the processing of the data is Art. 6 Para. 1 Item b GDPR.

The legal basis for the disclosure of personal data to communications service providers, to a collection agency, to legal representatives or to the competent court is Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GDPR.

Insofar as the retention of data is necessary in connection with the conclusion of contract for the fulfilment of a legal obligation, in particular obligations to provide evidence under corporate and tax law, to which our company is subject, Art. 6 Para. 1 Item c GDPR serves as the legal basis.

If invoices are sent by post or communication is made by post, your name and your address may be passed on to our service provider WienIT GmbH, Thomas-Klestil-Platz 3, 1030 Vienna for printing and enveloping.

#### **6.3. Purpose of the data processing**

The data processing is necessary for the fulfilment of a contract with the user or for the performance of pre-contractual measures.

#### **6.4. Duration of the storage**

The data is deleted or anonymised as soon as it is no longer required for the achievement of the purpose for which it was collected. For example, the data provided during registration will be automatically deleted 14 days after registration if the user does not subsequently purchase any products or services. Any inquiries about terms or the last four digits of the credit card will not be saved but discarded immediately after retrieval.

This is the case for data that has been collected for the purpose of fulfilling a contract or for carrying out a pre-contractual measure once the data is no longer necessary for the performance or the documentation of the contract.

This is the case for data that has been collected for the fulfilment of a contract or for the performance of a pre-contractual measure once the data is no longer necessary for the performance or the documentation of the contract. There may still be a need to store personal data even after the end of the contractual relationship in order to comply with contractual or statutory obligations. The data that is required for the fulfilment of obligations to provide evidence under corporate and tax law in connection with the contract is deleted or anonymised upon the expiry of the seventh calendar year after the end of the contractual relationship, unless there are further statutory obligations that require longer storage.

Backup copies in our backup systems are automatically deleted with a time delay.

#### **6.5. Option to object or request elimination**

As a user, you have the option to terminate concluded contracts within the scope of the conditions agreed upon therein. If necessary, you may have the data stored on you rectified at any time.

If the data is necessary for the fulfillment of a contract or for the performance of pre-contractual measures, earlier erasure of the data is not possible.

### **7\. Contact and feedback forms**

#### **7.1. Description and scope of the data processing**

Our website contains contact forms that can be used to establish contact electronically. If a user makes use of this option, the data entered into the input screen is transmitted to us and stored by us.

For the processing of the data, your consent is obtained during the sending of the contact form, and reference is made to this data privacy statement.

No data is disclosed to third parties in this context. The data is used exclusively for the processing of the conversation. As part of the optional disclosure of the e-mail-address in the contact field of the FAQs the e-mail-address will be sent to our service provider Dixa ApS, Vimmelskaftet 41 A, 1. Stock, 1161 Copenhagen K, Denmark.

#### **7.2. Legal basis for the data processing**

If consent has been obtained from the user, the legal basis for the processing of the data is Art. 6 Para. 1 Item a GDPR.

If the establishment of contact is undertaken with the aim of concluding a contract, Art. 6 Para. 1 Item b GDPR serves as an additional legal basis for the processing.

#### **7.3. Purpose of the data processing**

The processing of the personal data from the input screen serves exclusively to help us process the contact inquiry.

The other personal data processed during the sending of the contact form serves to prevent misuse of the contact form and to ensure the security of our information technology systems.

#### **7.4. Duration of the storage**

The data is deleted as soon as it is no longer required for the achievement of the purpose for which it was collected. For the personal data from the input screen of the contact form, this is the case once the communication is no longer expected to be continued on the part of the user. It is assumed that this is the case after three years.

For the personal data additionally collected during the sending of the contact form, the same applies as for the log files above under III.

#### **7.5. Option to object or request elimination**

The user has the option to revoke his or her consent to the processing of the personal data at any time via email.

In this case, all personal data that has been stored in the scope of the contact inquiry will be deleted, unless this data is necessary for the fulfilment of a contract or for the performance of pre-contractual measures.

### **8\. Chatbot-feature**

#### **8.1. Description and scope of the data processing**

On our website we use chatbot features by Dixa ApS, Vimmelskaftet 41 A, 1. Stock, 1161 Copenhagen K, Denmark. The use of the chatbot function is optional. For the purpose of customer service, the following personal data provided when entering the chat will be used in any case:

* First name, last name
* Customer number
* Domain

Other use of personal data may be necessary for the processing of customer service.

#### **8.2. Legal basis for the data processing**

The legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 Para. 1 Item. b GDPR (contract fulfillment) and Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f (legitimate interest).  
In the course of fulfilling the contract, the data is processed in accordance with Art. 6 Para.1 Item. b DSGVO for a period of up to 180 days after the end of the conversation.

#### **8.3. Purpose of the data processing**

The purpose of the data processing is the exercise of customer service in connection with the performance of the contract and our legitimate interest.  
When using the chatbot functions, data is transmitted directly to the servers of our service provider Dixa AG, which are located in Denmark. You can find more information about data protection at Dixa under [https://www.dixa.com/legal/privacy/.](https://www.dixa.com/legal/privacy/)  

#### **8.4. Duration of the storage**

The personal data of the customers are kept for up to 180 days after the end of the conversation. After that, the data processed in the chat will be anonymized.

#### **8.5. Option to object or request elimination**

As a user, you have the option to terminate concluded contracts within the scope of the conditions agreed upon therein. If necessary, you may have the data stored on you rectified at any time.  
If the data is necessary for the fulfilment of a contract or for the performance of pre-contractual measures, earlier erasure of the data is not possible.

### **9\. AI domain search**

#### **9.1. Description and scope of data processing**

On our website, it is possible to generate domain suggestions using artificial intelligence (AI). If you take advantage of this option, the data entered in the input mask will be transmitted to the external service OpenAI Ireland Limited, 1st Floor, The Liffey Trust Centre, 117-126 Sheriff Street Upper, Dublin 1, D01 YC43, Ireland. Only the data entered in the form will be transmitted to the third-party provider.  
We obtain your consent using the checkbox in the terms of use and the reference to this privacy policy.

As part of this service, data is transferred to the USA or cannot be ruled out. The ECJ does not consider the USA to have an adequate level of data protection compared to EU standards (ECJ, C-311/18, Schrems II), in particular because your data can be processed by US authorities for surveillance purposes without you having effective legal protection against such measures.

#### **9.2. Legal basis for data processing**

The legal basis for the use of the AI domain search is the consent given (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR).

#### **9.3. Purpose of data processing**

The purpose of processing your data is to generate domain name suggestions using AI. The AI outputs are checked for the availability of domain names and issued as a recommendation.

#### **9.4. Further information on AI Domainchecker**

Please refrain from entering personal or person-related data in the input mask. 

world4you uses the AI Domainchecker tool from our service provider Ionos SE, Elgendorfer Str. 57, 56410 Montabaur, Germany. The following data is transmitted to our service provider Ionos SE:

* Total input of the user 
* Set language of the user 
* Generated domain name of the AI

Your data will be deleted after one year. world4you is neither a provider nor a contractual partner for the use of AI services, nor is world4you liable for the results of AI and only offers the integration of AI systems. The use of AI or related tools is subject to data processing and data transfer to third parties, such as OpenAI.

Any use is subject to OpenAI's terms of use. To exercise your legal rights, such as your right to deletion, you can do so through your OpenAI account. If you do not have one, you can submit your request at [https://privacy.openai.com](https://privacy.openai.com/) or by email to dsar@openai.com.

### **10\. Applications**

#### **10.1. Description and scope of the data processing**

For the purpose of advertising job vacancies and receiving applications, we operate an application platform on our website.

We process the data submitted to us by applicants in the course of the application.

#### **10.2. Legal basis for the data processing**

The legal bases for the processing are Art. 6 Para. 1 Item b GDPR (pre-contractual measures) and Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GDPR as well as, in the event that the applicant consents to the keeping on file of an application, Art. 6 Para. 1 Item a GDPR.

#### **10.3. Purpose of the data processing**

The purposes of the data processing are the realisation of the application procedure and the correspondence with the applicant as well as the keeping on file of applications and the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

#### **10.4. Duration of the storage**

If you apply for a job vacancy and are not hired, we store the personal data for seven months from the end of the application procedure (a period of six months for the establishment of claims pursuant to §§ 15 Para. 1 and 29 GlBG (Equal Treatment Act) plus one month to allow for potential legal action) on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GDPR.

If the applicant provides his/her consent in the respective individual case, we keep the specific application documents on file for the respective period agreed upon during the granting of consent, for a maximum, however, of 5 years.

If the application is unsolicited, we process the application documents for a maximum of two years on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GPDR so as to be able to contact the applicant if a suitable job vacancy becomes available, whereby an objection to the processing may be filed at any time.

In the event that an employment relationship is established, the application documents are further used for the purpose of personnel administration.

#### **10.5. Option to object or request elimination**

The applicant has the option to revoke his/her consent to the keeping on file of an application at any time via email or letter.

An objection may be filed to the processing of the data from an unsolicited application at any time via email or letter.

### **12\. Protection against cyber attacks using Wordfence**

We have integrated Wordfence into this website. The provider is Defiant Inc, Defiant, Inc, 800 5th Ave Ste 4100, Seattle, WA 98104, USA (hereinafter referred to as Wordfence).

Wordfence protects our website from unwanted access or malicious cyberattacks. To do this, our website establishes a permanent connection to Wordfence’s servers so that Wordfence can check its databases against the accesses made to our website and block them if necessary. The use of Wordfence is based on Article 6 Para. 1 (f) of the GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in protecting its website against cyberattacks as effectively as possible. The data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. You can find details here: [https://www.wordfence.com/help/general-data-protection-regulation/](https://www.wordfence.com/help/general-data-protection-regulation/) .

We have concluded an order processing contract with Wordfence. This is a contract required by data protection law and ensures that Wordfence processes the personal data of our website visitors strictly in accordance with our instructions and in compliance with the GDPR.

In exceptional cases, from which website users are usually not affected, Wordfence uses cookies. Below, we explain what each cookie does, which users the cookie is set for and how the cookie helps protect the site.

(1) wfwaf-authcookie- (Hash): This cookie is used by the Wordfence firewall to carry out a capability check on the current user before WordPress loads. It’s only set for users who can log into WordPress. The Wordfence firewall uses this cookie to recognise logged-in users and allow them increased access. Wordfence can also detect users who are not logged in and restrict their access to secure areas. The cookie informs the firewall what level of access a visitor has, so that the firewall can make informed decisions about who should be allowed and who should be blocked.

(2) wf\_loginalerted\_ (Hash): This cookie is used to notify the Wordfence administrator when an administrator logs in from a new device or location. This cookie is set for administrators only and is used to help site operators know if an admin has logged in from a new device or location.

(3) wfCBLBypass: Wordfence offers a site visitor the option of bypassing country blocking by accessing a hidden URL. This cookie can be used to track who can bypass country blocking. When a hidden URL defined by the site administrator is accessed, this cookie is used to check whether the user can access the site from a country restricted by country blocking. This is set for anyone who knows the URL that enables the default country blocking to be bypassed. This cookie is not set for anyone who does not know the hidden URL to bypass country blocking. This cookie gives site owners the ability to allow certain users of blocked countries even though their country has been blocked.

### **12\. Web analysis by Google Analytics (Analysis cookies)**

#### **12.1. Scope of the processing of personal data**

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies”, text files that are stored on your computer and that enable the analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this website (including your IP address) is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google will use this information to assess your use of the website, to compile reports on the website activities for the website operators and to provide further services connected to the use of the website and the use of the internet. Google may potentially also transfer this information to third parties if required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google. Under no circumstances will Google link your IP address to other data.

You can prevent the storage of the cookies by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser software; furthermore, you can prevent the recording of the data generated by the cookie as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the following link: [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en) . However, we must point out that in this case, you may not be able to use all the functions of this website to their full extent.

IP anonymisation: We use the function “activation of the IP anonymisation” on this website. This means that your IP address is first shortened by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area before it is transmitted to the USA and thus anonymised. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there.

By consenting to the use of analysis cookies, at the same time you agree pursuant to Art. 49 Para. 1 Item a GDPR that your data may be processed in the USA. The ECJ does not confirm an appropriate data protection level for the USA that matches the EU standards (ECJ, C-311/18, Schrems II), especially since your data may be processed by the US authorities for monitoring purposes without any effective legal protection being available against such measures.

More information on how Google Analytics handles user data is available in Google’s data privacy statement: [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en) .

#### **12.2. Legal basis for the processing of personal data**

The legal basis for the processing of users' personal data is the consent of the person concerned in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 Item f GDPR.

#### **12.3. Purpose of the data processing**

The processing of the personal data of the users enables us to analyse our users’ browsing habits. By evaluating the data obtained, we are able to compile information on the use of the individual components of our website. This helps us to constantly improve our website and its user-friendliness.

#### **12.4. Duration of the storage**

The data is deleted as soon as it is no longer required for our record-keeping purposes. The evaluations are performed using aggregated, and thus no longer personal, data.

#### **12.5. Option to object or request elimination**

Cookies are stored on the user’s computer and transmitted to us from there. Hence you as the user have complete control over the use of cookies. By changing the settings in your internet browser, you can deactivate or limit the transmission of cookies. Cookies that have already been stored can be deleted at any time. This can also be carried out automatically. If cookies are deactivated for our website, it is possible that you may no longer be able to use all the functions of the website to their full extent.

### **13\. Analysis of user behavior using Mouseflow**

#### **13.1. Scope of the processing of personal data**

On our website we use the tool from Mouseflow ApS, Flaesketorvet 68, 1711 Copenhage, Denmark. The following data is transmitted to the service provider Mouseflow ApS for the purpose of improving user experience: 

* anonymized IP-adress
* device type
* date and time of the website visit
* user behavior on the website

#### **13.2. Legal basis for the data processing**

The legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 para. 1 item a (consent). We obtain this via the cookie banner. 

#### **13.3. Purpose of data processing**

The processing of the personal data of the users enables us to analyse our users’ browsing habits. By evaluating the data obtained, we are able to compile information on the use of the individual components of our website. This helps us to constantly improve our website and its user-friendliness.

#### **13.4. Duration of the storage**

The data is deleted as soon as it is no longer required for our record-keeping purposes. The evaluations are performed using aggregated, and thus no longer personal, data.

#### **13.5. Option to object or request elimination**

Cookies are stored on the user’s computer and transmitted to us from there. Hence you as the user have complete control over the use of cookies. By changing the settings in your internet browser, you can deactivate or limit the transmission of cookies. Cookies that have already been stored can be deleted at any time. This can also be carried out automatically. If cookies are deactivated for our website, it is possible that you may no longer be able to use all the functions of the website to their full extent.

### **14\. Remarketing (Marketing Cookies)**

This website uses Google’s remarketing function. The function serves to present advertisements of interest to the website visitors within the Google advertising network. This technology enables us to display automatically created, target group-oriented advertisements after your visit to our website. The displays are based on the products and services that you clicked on during your last visit to our website. To this end, a so-called “cookie” is stored in the browser of the website visitor, which makes it possible to recognise the visitor when he calls up websites that belong to the Google advertising network. Cookies are small text files that are stored in your browser when you visit our website. Normally, Google stores information such as your web request, the IP address, the browser type, the browser language, the date and the time of your request. This information serves to associate the web browser with a specific computer. On the web pages of the Google advertising network, advertisements can subsequently be presented to the visitor that are related to contents that the visitor previously called up on websites that use Google’s remarketing function.

You as the user have the option to deactivate the use of cookies by Google; you can do so by calling up the page to deactivate Google at [https://www.google.com/ads/preferences](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences) . You can view more detailed information on Google remarketing as well as Google’s data privacy statement at: [https://www.google.com/privacy/ads/](https://www.google.com/privacy/ads/) .

By consenting to the use of marketing cookies, at the same time you agree pursuant to Art. 49 Para. 1 Item a GDPR that your data may be processed in the USA. The ECJ does not confirm an appropriate data protection level for the USA that matches the EU standards (ECJ, C-311/18, Schrems II), especially since your data may be processed by the US authorities for monitoring purposes without any effective legal protection being available against such measures.

We use "Facebook pixels" from Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA, or for residents of the European Union, the European Economic Area and Switzerland, Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbor, Dublin 2, Ireland ("Facebook"). When you visit our website, a direct connection between your browser and the Facebook server is established via the Facebook Pixel. As a result, Facebook receives the information that you have visited our site with your IP address. This enables Facebook to assign your visit to our website to your user account. We can use the information obtained in this way to display Facebook ads or for tracking functions. The data collected are anonymous for us as the operator.

You can find more information on this in Facebook's data protection declaration at [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) . If you do not wish to collect data via Custom Audience, you can deactivate it here [https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry\_product=ad\_settings\_screen](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen) . You must first log into Facebook. If you do not have a Facebook account, you can suppress usage-based advertising from Facebook on the website of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance: [https://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/) .

On the website we use technologies from Bing Ads (bingads.microsoft.com), which are provided and operated by Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA ("Microsoft"). Microsoft places a cookie on your device if you have reached our website via a Microsoft Bing ad. In this way, Microsoft and we can recognize that someone has clicked on an ad, has been redirected to our website and has reached a previously determined target page ("conversion site"). We only find out the total number of users who clicked on a Bing ad and were then redirected to the conversion site. Microsoft collects, processes and uses information via the cookie, from which usage profiles are created using pseudonyms. These usage profiles are used to analyze visitor behavior and are used to display advertisements. No personal information about the identity of the user is processed. If you do not want information about your behavior from Microsoft to be used as explained above, you can refuse the setting of a cookie required for this - for example via a browser setting that generally deactivates the automatic setting of cookies.

You can also prevent the collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website and the processing of this data by Microsoft by clicking on the following link [https://choice.microsoft.com/de-DE/opt-out](https://choice.microsoft.com/de-DE/opt-out) explain out your contradiction. Further information on data protection and the cookies used by Microsoft and Bing Ads can be found on the Microsoft website [https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement](https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement) .

If you do not change any settings or delete anything in your internet browser, the marketing cookies will remain valid for one month, with the exception of the following cookies, which remain valid for three months:

* \_gcl\_au
* \_fbp

### **15\. Analysis by Jentis GmbH**

For the purpose of analysing the user behaviour of customers and for the purpose of website optimisation, we use services of JENTIS GmbH (Schönbrunner Strasse 231, 1120 Vienna, Austria). This service provider therefore receives access to web analysis data, which are measured, stored and made available by the utilised analysis tools and JENTIS®.

On the one hand, data is transmitted to JENTIS GmbH for analysis purposes, on the other hand JENTIS® on our behalf independently collects data relating to the browser environment or the behaviour of the visitor. JENTIS GmbH only processes data that JENTIS GmbH cannot trace back to a person. IDs set by JENTIS® are merely random products and are used for anonymous recognition. Your IP address will be shortened before storage so that no personal reference is required.

### **16\. LinkedIn Insight Conversion Tool**

We use the LinkedIn Insight Conversion Tool of LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, which allows us to obtain information about the use of our website and to provide you with advertising content on other websites that is tailored to your interests. For this purpose, a cookie with a validity of 120 days is set in your browser, which enables LinkedIn to recognize you when you visit a website. LinkedIn uses this data to create anonymous reports on ad activity and information about how you interact with our website.

You can disable the LinkedIn Insight Conversion Tool and interest-based advertising by opting out at the following link: [https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/ads](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/ads) .

By consenting to the use of marketing cookies, at the same time you agree pursuant to Art. 49 Para. 1 Item a GDPR that your data may be processed in the USA. The ECJ does not confirm an appropriate data protection level for the USA that matches the EU standards (ECJ, C-311/18, Schrems II), especially since your data may be processed by the US authorities for monitoring purposes without any effective legal protection being available against such measures.

Find more information on data protection at LinkedIn here: [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy#choices-oblig](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy#choices-oblig) .

### **17\. Personalization Engine**

In the customer area, in which you can log in as a customer of ours, we use the Personalization Engine tool from Ionos SE, Elgendorfer Str. 57, 56410 Montabaur, Germany (former name: "Ad Server"). This function is used to show you information and personalized offers in the customer area. For this purpose, your following data are transmitted to our service provider Ionos SE:  

* language
* customer number
* first name
* last name 
* company name
* date of your registration
* gender “unknown”
* telephone number 
* e-mail address
* address (street, number, ZIP-code, city, state)
* data of products/packages (product IDs, purchase date for the product/service, product definition ID, product description, product category)
* 2FA-authentication active/inactive

The legal basis for the processing of user's personal data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The respective data will be deleted at the end of the session.

On the website, we use the Personalization Engine tool for web tracking of website users. For this purpose, the following data is transmitted to our service provider Ionos SE:

* Full URL accessed
* Title of the page accessed
* Scroll position

The legal basis for the processing of users' personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR (consent). The respective data is deleted 365 days after the last visit.

### **18\. Reddit Pixel (Conversion Tracking)**

Purpose: Marketing  
Recipient country: USA

On our website we use the Reddit Conversion Pixel, an analysis service of Reddit Inc., 520 Third Street, Suite 305, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA ("Reddit").

Within the scope of this service, data is transmitted to the USA or such transmission cannot be ruled out. We would like to point out that, in the opinion of the European Court of Justice, there is currently no adequate level of data protection in the case of data transfer to the USA and that there are therefore various risks (such as possible access by US secret services).

For this tool, a so-called tracking pixel is integrated on our website. When you visit our pages, a direct connection is established between your browser and the Reddit server via this tracking pixel. Reddit thereby receives, among other things, the information from your browser that our page was called up from your end device. We would like to point out that we have no influence on the scope of the transmitted data and its further use by Reddit and therefore inform you according to our state of knowledge: Through the integration of Reddit conversion pixels, Reddit receives the information that you have called up the corresponding web page of our website or clicked on an advertisement from us. If you are registered with a Reddit service, Reddit can assign the visit to your account. Even if you are not registered with Reddit or have not logged in, it is possible that the provider will find out and store your IP address and other identifying features.

The processing of your data is based on your consent within the meaning of Art. 6 paragraph 1 lit. a GDPR. You can revoke this consent at any time with effect for the future. 

You can find more information on data protection and your settings options in this regard at [https://www.redditinc.com/policies/privacy-policy](https://www.redditinc.com/policies/privacy-policy)

### **19\. TikTok Pixel**

On our website, we use the so-called TikTok pixel of the social network TikTok, which is operated by TikTok Technology Limited, 10 Earlsfort Terrace, Dublin, D02 T380, Ireland ("TikTok"). The parent company of TikTok is based in China.

**ATTENTION: Within the scope of this service, data transfer to China takes place or cannot be ruled out.**

With the help of the TikTok pixel, it is possible for TikTok, on the one hand, to determine you as a visitor to our online offer as a target group for the display of advertisements (so-called "TikTok ads"). Accordingly, we use the TikTok pixel to display the TikTok ads placed by us only to those TikTok users who have also shown an interest in our online offer or who have certain characteristics (e.g. interests in certain topics or products determined on the basis of the websites visited) that we transmit to TikTok (so-called "Custom Audiences").

With the help of the TikTok pixel, we also want to ensure that our TikTok ads correspond to the potential interest of users and are not harassing. The TikTok pixel also allows us to track the effectiveness of the TikTok ads for statistical and market research purposes by seeing whether users have been redirected to our website after clicking on a TikTok ad (so-called "conversion").

The processing of the data by TikTok takes place within the framework of the data use policy at [https://www.tiktok.com/legal/privacy-policy?lang=en of TikTok](https://www.tiktok.com/legal/privacy-policy?lang=en%20of%20TikTok) .

Specific information and details about the TikTok Pixel and how it works can be found in the TikTok help section at [https://support.tiktok.com/en](https://support.tiktok.com/en)

The use of the TikTok pixel as well as the storage of "conversion cookies" is based on your consent according to Art. 6 paragraph 1 lit. a GDPR. You can revoke this consent at any time.

For the processing of data for which TikTok acts as a data processor, we have concluded a data processing agreement with TikTok in which we oblige TikTok to protect our customers' data and not to pass it on to third parties.

### **20\. Rights of the data subjects**

If you wish to exercise any of your rights mentioned below (lit a to g), please contact us via dataprotection@world4you.com and we will process your request.

a) Right of access (Art. 15 GDPR)

You have the right to receive information about the personal data saved about your person at any time and to receive a copy of this information.

b) Right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR)

You have the right to demand the rectification and/or completion of incorrect and/or incomplete personal data about you.

c) Right to erasure (Art. 17 GDPR)

You have the right to trigger the deletion of your personal data held by us. The data will be deleted immediately, if you request this.

However, in certain cases, your data cannot be erased:

* if these data are still needed for an active contract;
* if this is contrary to statutory retention periods or the erasure is opposed by contrary interests. In this case, however, processing of the data for other purposes may be blocked.

d) Right to restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR)

You have the right to demand a restriction of processing if one of the following prerequisites applies:

* You dispute the correctness of the personal data, for a duration which enables us to review the correctness of the personal data.
* The processing is unlawful, you reject the erasure of the personal data and instead demand a restriction of the use of the personal data.
* We no longer need the personal data for the purpose of processing, but you need this to assert, exercise or defend against legal claims.
* You have raised an objection against the processing pursuant to Art. 21 para. 1 GDPR and it is not yet clear whether our legitimate grounds override yours.

e) Right to object (Art. 21 GDPR)

You have the right to object at any time to the processing of the personal data relating to you in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. e or f GDPR.

In case of an objection, we no longer process the personal data, except where we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms or the processing serves the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

You have the right to object at any time to processing of personal data for the purpose of direct advertising.

f) Right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR)

You have the right to receive the personal data concerning you, which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and transfer them to a third party.

You also have the right to transmit those data to another controller without hindrance from us where the processing is based on consent pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR or Art. 9 para. 2 lit a GDPR or on a contract pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR and the processing is carried out by automated means, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller.

Furthermore, in exercising your right to data portability pursuant to Art. 20 para. 1 GDPR, you shall have the right to have the personal data transmitted directly from one controller to another, where technically feasible, and this does not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

g) Right to withdraw consent under data protection law (Art. 7 para. 3 GDPR)

You have the right to withdraw the consent granted by you for the processing of your personal data at any time with effect for the future.

**Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (Art. 77 GDPR)**

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the competent supervisory authority at any time.

**Linz**, on  16\. December 2024

### **Enabling and disabling cookies in the browser**

You can enable or disable the general use of cookies in your browser. Depending on the browser you use, you can find these settings in the options menu of your browser. When you open the [privacy settings](#) , you can choose whether to agree to the use of cookies on our pages without restriction or to allow only certain cookies.

### About cookies

Cookies are small data packages that are exchanged between your browser and our web server. Cookies can only store information provided by your browser.

Depending on the intended use, cookies are either technically necessary or are used for statistical or marketing purposes. The use of technically required cookies is based on our legitimate interest in the technically correct operation and smooth functionality of our website. The use of statistics and marketing cookies requires your consent. This is voluntary and can be revoked at any time for the future by calling up our cookie settings.

You can also set your browser to generally prevent the storage of cookies. Once cookies have been set, you can delete them at any time. How all this works in details can be found in the help function of your browser. Please note that a general deactivation of cookies may lead to functional restrictions on our website.

You can find more detailed information on what data is stored in cookies, for what purposes they are used and for how long data is stored in our data protection declaration and in our cookie banner.

#### Required

Technically necessary cookies are used to enable the technical operation of a website and make it functional for you. The use is based on our legitimate interest to provide a technically flawless website. However, you can generally disable the use of cookies in your browser. 

| Surname | Purpose | Creator | Storage time | Domain |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **\_color\_system\_schema** | ensures the functionality and usability of the page and is used to track errors. |     | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **cookieconsent\_mode** | contains the information to what extent the user has confirmed the use of cookies. | DataReporter GmbH | 12 months | www.world4you.com |
| **cookieconsent\_status** | contains the information to what extent the user has confirmed the use of cookies. | DataReporter GmbH | 12 months | www.world4you.com |
| **mf\_(ID)** | ensures the functionality and usability of the page and is used to track errors. |     | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **mf\_user** | counts the number of sessions and assigns an anonymous identifier to each visitor. |     | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **sessionId** | counts the number of sessions and assigns an anonymous identifier to each visitor. |     | Session | my.world4you.com |
| **ssm\_au\_c** | save settings and preferences of the user such as the current language setting. | Cloudflare | Session | my.world4you.com |
| **ti\_cid** | ensures the functionality and usability of the page and is used to track errors. |     | 12 months | world4you.com |
| **W4YSESSID** | counts the number of sessions and assigns an anonymous identifier to each visitor. |     | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **xtx\_search\_id** | ensures the functionality and usability of the page and is used to track errors. |     | Session | my.world4you.com |

#### Statistics

Statistics cookies collect information about how websites are used to improve their attractiveness, content and functionality. A use takes place only with your consent and only as long as you have not deactivated the respective cookie.

| Surname | Purpose | Creator | Storage time | Domain |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **\_ga** | Contains information to help distinguish users from the page. Gathers data about user visits, such as which pages are relevant. | Google | 1 year | world4you.com |
| **\_ga\_(GA4-ID)** | Contains information to help distinguish users from the page. Gathers data about user visits, such as which pages are relevant. | Google | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **\_gac\_(GA-ID)** | Contains information to help distinguish users from the page. Gathers data about user visits, such as which pages are relevant. | Google | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **\_gat** | Contains information to help distinguish users from the page. Gathers data about user visits, such as which pages are relevant. | Google | 1 minute | world4you.com |
| **\_gcl\_au** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Google | 3 months | world4you.com |
| **\_gid** | Contains information to help distinguish users from the page. Gathers data about user visits, such as which pages are relevant. | Google | 1 day | world4you.com |
| **\_pk\_testcookie.(ID)** | Contains information to help distinguish users from the page. Gathers data about user visits, such as which pages are relevant. | Matomo/Piwik | Session | my.world4you.com |
| **\_pk\_testcookie..undefined** | Contains information to help distinguish users from the page. Gathers data about user visits, such as which pages are relevant. | Matomo/Piwik | Session | my.world4you.com |
| **jts-rw** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Jentis | 1 year | world4you.com |
| **jts\_ga** | Contains information to help distinguish users from the page. Gathers data about user visits, such as which pages are relevant. | Google | Session | my.world4you.com |
| **jts\_ga\_HMVMP3XZDE** | Contains information to help distinguish users from the page. Gathers data about user visits, such as which pages are relevant. | Google Analytics | Session | my.world4you.com |

#### Marketing

Marketing cookies come from external advertising companies and are used to collect information about the websites visited by the user. A use takes place only with your consent and only as long as you have not deactivated the respective cookie.

| Surname | Purpose | Creator | Storage time | Domain |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **\_fbc** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Facebook | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **\_fbp** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Facebook | 3 months | world4you.com |
| **\_gcl\_aw** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Google | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **\_gcl\_dc** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Google | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **\_gcl\_gb** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Google | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **\_gcl\_gs** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Google | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **bcookie** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | LinkedIn | 12 months | linkedin.com |
| **IDE** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Google | 1 year | doubleclick.net |
| **jts-fbc** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. |     | Session | www.world4you.com |
| **jts-fbp** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. |     | 3 months | world4you.com |
| **li\_gc** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | LinkedIn | 6 months | linkedin.com |
| **lidc** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | LinkedIn | 1 day | linkedin.com |
| **NID** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Google |     | www.google.com |
| **test\_cookie** | registers a unique ID that identifies and recognizes the user. Used for targeted advertising. | Google | 15 minutes | doubleclick.net |

* * *

* Services
* Products
* Company
* Support

© 2024 World4You Internet Services GmbH, all prices include 20% VAT.

We'll be back in a moment!
